<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "RestComm_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<!-- chapter id nickname: ittsss -->
<chapter>
	<title>Configuration</title>
	<para>In order to make RestComm easy to manage all of the configuration is done in only one file.
		The file is located at <filename>PATH_TO_DEPLOYMENT_DIRECTORY/restcomm/conf/restcomm.xml</filename>
		and is composed of the following sections:</para>
	<table frame='all'>
		<title>Configuration Sections</title>
		<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
			<colspec colname='c1' />
			<colspec colname='c2' />
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry align="center">Section</entry>
					<entry align="center">Description</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>runtime-settings</entry>
					<entry>Settings that RestComm will use at runtime to make decisions.</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>dao-manager</entry>
					<entry>
					  Manages the data store used by RestComm. The default implementation is based on MyBatis and is used
					  to interact with RDBMS systems. Alternatively, RestComm now ships with a MongoDB implementations as
					  well.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>media-server-manager</entry>
					<entry>
					  Manages media servers managed by RestComm and the connections to them. The media server manager
					  also implements load-balancing across the media servers. The current implementation is round-robin
					  but in future releases media server load will dictate how connections are managed.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>sms-aggregator</entry>
					<entry>
					  Manages SMS service providers. Please keep in mind that not all SMS providers support all the functionality
					  offered by RestComm and therefore, certain SMS related feature may be related. Refer to the appropriate
					  documentation for more information.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>speech-synthesizer</entry>
					<entry>
					  A text to speech synthesizer for RestComm. The default implementation uses the Acapela Group TTS service.
					  In future releases we are planning on supporting all the major service providers.
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
	<section>
		<title>Runtime Settings</title>
		<para>
		  The runtime-settings are used by RestComm at runtime to make important decisions. A list of the runtime settings
		  and a descriptions is provided below.
		</para>
			
		<table frame='all'>
			<title>Runtime Settings</title>
			<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
				<colspec colname='c1' />
				<colspec colname='c2' />
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry align="center">Element</entry>
						<entry align="center">Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>beep-audio-file</entry>
						<entry>The audio file to play for the 'beep' and 'playBeep' attributes.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>reject-audio-file</entry>
						<entry>The audio file to play for the &lt;Reject&gt; verb using the 'rejected' attribute.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>silence-audio-file</entry>
						<entry>
						  This file has one second of silence and is used to insert &lt;Pause&gt; verbs in the &lt;Gather&gt;
						  verb as a prompt that can be played by the media server.
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>recordings-path</entry>
						<entry>
						  The path to the directory used to save recordings made by RestComm.
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>recordings-uri</entry>
						<entry>
						  The HTTP URI to the recordings directory.
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>outbound-proxy-user</entry>
						<entry>
						  The user name used to authenticate with the outbound proxy. (Optional)
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>outbound-proxy-password</entry>
						<entry>
						  The password used to authenticated with the outbound proxy. (Optional)
						</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>outbound-proxy-uri</entry>
						<entry>
						  The SIP URI to the outbound proxy. Note: Do not prepend 'sip:' to the proxy uri.
						</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Dao Manager</title>
		<para>The data access object manager is used to gain access to the data store that RestComm will use.</para>
			
		<para>The default data access object manager is based on MyBatis and provides access to RDBM systems. Alternatively,
		  a MongoDB implementation is included.</para>
		
		<table frame='all'>
			<title>MyBatis Settings</title>
			<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
				<colspec colname='c1' />
				<colspec colname='c2' />
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry align="center">Element</entry>
						<entry align="center">Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>datasource</entry>
						<entry>The JNDI data source to use.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>configuration-file</entry>
						<entry>The path to the mybatis.xml configuration file.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>sql-files</entry>
						<entry>The path to the XML files containing the SQL statements that will be executed by the database.</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
		
		<table frame='all'>
			<title>MongoDB Settings</title>
			<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
				<colspec colname='c1' />
				<colspec colname='c2' />
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry align="center">Element</entry>
						<entry align="center">Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>host</entry>
						<entry>The IP address or host name of MongoDB server.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>port</entry>
						<entry>The port on the MongoDB server to use.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>database</entry>
						<entry>The name of the database to use.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>user</entry>
						<entry>The user name used to authenticate with MongoDB (Optional).</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>password</entry>
						<entry>The password used to authenticate with MongoDB (Optional).</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Media Server Manager</title>
		
		<para>
		  The media server manager is responsible for all the media servers managed by RestComm. The media server manager
		  is also responsible for load-balancing connections to the media servers that it manages. Currently, load-balancing
		  uses a naive round-robin implementation but in future implementations the algorithm will be based on media server
		  load.
		  
		  When configuring the media server manager multiple media server can be defined. Below is a description of settings
		  for each media server.
		</para>
		
		<table frame='all'>
			<title>Media Server Manager Settings</title>
			<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
				<colspec colname='c1' />
				<colspec colname='c2' />
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry align="center">Property</entry>
						<entry align="center">Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>local-address</entry>
						<entry>The local IP address for the MGCP stack.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>local-port</entry>
						<entry>The local port for the MGCP stack.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>remote-address</entry>
						<entry>The IP address for the media server.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>remote-port</entry>
						<entry>The port for the media server.</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>SMS Aggregator</title>
		<para>The SMS aggregator is responsible for the handling of SMS messages inside of RestComm.</para>
		
		<para>
		  The default SMS aggregator uses Essendex. Please know that in order to use SMS and account with Essendex
		  is required until support for more service providers is implemented.
		</para>
		
		<table frame='all'>
			<title>SMS Aggregator Settings</title>
			<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
				<colspec colname='c1' />
				<colspec colname='c2' />
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry align="center">Element</entry>
						<entry align="center">Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>user</entry>
						<entry>The user name used to authenticate with Essendex.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>password</entry>
						<entry>The password used to authenticate with Essendex.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>account</entry>
						<entry>The account used to authenticate with Essendex.</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Speech Synthesizer</title>
		<para>The speech synthesizer turns text to speech on behalf of RestComm.</para>
		
		<para>The default speech synthesizer uses the TTS service provided by the Acapela Group. Please know that in order to use
		  TTS an account with the Acapela Group is required until support for more service providers is implemented.</para>
		
		<table frame='all'>
			<title>Acapela Group Speech Synthesizer Settings</title>
			<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
				<colspec colname='c1' />
				<colspec colname='c2' />
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry align="center">Element</entry>
						<entry align="center">Description</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>cache-path</entry>
						<entry>The location on the file system to use for caching TTS results.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>service-root</entry>
						<entry>The acapela group service root URI.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>application</entry>
						<entry>The application used to authenticate with the acapela group.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>login</entry>
						<entry>The login used to authenticate with the acapela group.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>password</entry>
						<entry>The password used to authenticate with the acapela group.</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>speakers</entry>
						<entry>
						  A list of male and female speakers for different languages. These can be replaced
						  with other alternatives provided by the acapela group.
						</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</section>
</chapter>
