<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "RestComm_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter>
	<title>Introduction to &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME;</title>
	<para>&SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME;
		is a Communications Platform to rapidly build fax, voice, and text messaging
		applications, using your existing web development skills.
	</para>
	<para>
		It's a complete turnkey Telco 2.0 SaaS solution ready to deploy in
		your cloud based on the
		<ulink url="www.twilio.com">Twilio</ulink>
		simple and effective APIs and 100% Open Source built on the next
		generation Cloud Communications platform &PLATFORM_NAME;.
	</para>
	<section>
		<title>How it Works</title>
		<para>In order to demonstrate how &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME; works we will go over an application that
		instructs &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME; to answer a phone call, say "Hello World" and finally hang up the
		call.</para>
		<note>
			<para>A more thorough explanation of the &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME; Markup Language is available in Chapter 3. &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME;
		    Markup Language</para>
		</note>
		<para>In this particular example, the first thing that must happen is that RestComm receives a call.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/restcomm-inbound-1.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>After RestComm can confirm that the call is destined for an application that it handles. RestComm calls
		out to your application for instructions on how to handle the new incoming call. Keep in mind that when RestComm
		calls out to your application it provides useful information such as from what number the call was dialed, to
		what number the call is destined, caller ID information, etc.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/restcomm-inbound-2.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once your application responds with instructions on how to handle the call, RestComm gets busy executing the
		provided instruction set.</para>
		<programlisting role="XML">
		&lt;Response&gt;
		  &lt;Say&gt;Hello World!&lt;/Say&gt;
		&lt;/Response&gt;
		</programlisting>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/restcomm-inbound-3.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>In this case RestComm synthesizes the text to speech, says "Hello World!" to the caller and hangs up.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/restcomm-inbound-4.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<section>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <para>Okay... Lets get started! In this chapter we will go over the steps necessary to deploy and run RestComm on
      the local host for development. First we will discuss how to get started using the binary distribution and for
      those more adventurous of you we will then cover building from the source code.
      </para>
      <section>
        <title>Requirements</title>
        <para>RestComm is built as a SIP Servlet Application and has a couple of dependencies which are listed below.</para>
        <formalpara>
		  <title>Container (Required)</title>
		  <para>&SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME; supports &PLATFORM_NAME; Sip Servlets (JBoss AS5 - Tomcat 6.x - Tomcat 7.x)</para>
	    </formalpara>
	    <formalpara>
		  <title>Media Server (Required)</title>
		  <para>&SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME; supports Mobicents Media Server 3.0.0</para>
	    </formalpara>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
		<title>Using a binary distribution</title>
		<para>The easiest way to get started with RestComm is to download and unzip a binary distribution
		that includes Mobicents Sip Servlet Container + Mobicents Media Server + RestComm to your local machine.</para>
		<formalpara>
			<title>JBoss AS Binary Distribution</title>
			<para>In the next few steps we will deploy the RestComm binary that comes with the JBoss container. This
			process is very simple, it only requires a few steps:
				First, we download the zip file.
				Second, we unzip it.
				Third, we launch the Mobicents Media Server.
				Fourth and finally, we launch the JBoss container that already has RestComm pre-deployed.</para>
		</formalpara>
		<para>We will start by downloading the latest binary snapshot and unzipping it to the curring working directory.</para>
		<screen>
		~]$ wget https://mobicents.ci.cloudbees.com/job/RestComm/lastSuccessfulBuild/artifact/restcomm-saas-jboss-1.0.0.BETA2-SNAPSHOT.zip
		~]$ unzip restcomm-saas-jboss-1.0.0.BETA2-SNAPSHOT.zip
		</screen>
		<para>Okay now lets start the Mobicents Media Server and the JBoss Container.</para>
		<screen>
		~]$ cd restcomm-saas-jboss-1.0.0.BETA2-SNAPSHOT/mobicents-media-server/bin/
		~]$ chmod +x run.sh
		~]$ ./run.sh &amp;
		~]$ cd ../../bin
		~]$ ./run.sh &amp;
		</screen>
		<formalpara>
			<title>Tomcat Binary Distribution</title>
			<para>For those of you who need a more light-weight container we will also cover using a Tomcat based distribution in the
			following steps.</para>
		</formalpara>
		<screen>
		~]$ wget https://mobicents.ci.cloudbees.com/job/RestComm/lastSuccessfulBuild/artifact/restcomm-saas-tomcat-1.0.0.BETA2-SNAPSHOT.zip
		~]$ unzip restcomm-saas-tomcat-1.0.0.BETA2-SNAPSHOT.zip
		</screen>
		<para>Okay now lets start the Mobicents Media Server and the Tomcat Container.</para>
		<screen>
		~]$ cd restcomm-saas-tomcat-1.0.0.BETA2-SNAPSHOT/mobicents-media-server/bin/
		~]$ chmod +x run.sh
		~]$ ./run.sh &amp;
		~]$ cd ../../bin
		~]$ ./startup.sh
		</screen>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Building from source code</title>
		<para>In this section we will download the source code from the Git repository build RestComm and deploy it. This
		process has a few steps which we will explain as we execute them. Finally, we highly recommend using the containers
		supplied with the binary downloads as they have several extra libs in the lib folder to resolve database driver
		dependencies.</para>
		<para>We will start by downloading the source code from the Git repo on Google Code.</para>
		<screen>
		~]$ git clone https://code.google.com/p/restcomm/
		</screen>
		<para>Once we have the code we will build it using maven and run the regression test suite.</para>
		<screen>
		~]$ cd restcomm
		~]$ mvn clean install
		~]$ cd restcomm.core
		~]$ mvn clean install
		</screen>
		<para>The compiled distribution will be located in the <filename>restcomm</filename> directory and the archived WAR
		file wile be located in the <filename>restcomm.war</filename> file. Both of these will be located in the 
		<filename>target</filename> directory inside the <filename>restcomm.core</filename> directory which should be
		the current working directory. To deploy the war file you would first remove restcomm if it's already deployed in the
		container and then redeploy it by copying the WAR file to the appropriate directory.</para>
		<formalpara>
			<title>Deploying RestComm to the JBoss Container</title>
			<para>In order to deploy RestComm to the JBoss Container we will first remove the version that comes pre-deployed
			and then we will copy our <filename>restcomm</filename> directory with the compiled distribution to the
			<filename>deploy</filename> directory.</para>
		</formalpara>
		<screen>
		~]$ rm -r $JBOSS_HOME/server/default/deploy/restcomm.war
		~]$ cp -r target/restcomm $JBOSS_HOME/server/default/deploy/restcomm.war
		</screen>
		<formalpara>
			<title>Deploying RestComm to the Tomcat Container</title>
			<para>In order to deploy RestComm to the Tomcat Container we will first remove the version that comes pre-deployed
			and then we will copy our <filename>restcomm</filename> directory with the compiled distribution to the
			<filename>webapps</filename> directory.</para>
		</formalpara>
		<screen>
		~]$ rm -r $TOMCAT_HOME/webapps/restcomm
		~]$ cp -r target/restcomm $TOMCAT_HOME/webapps/restcomm
		</screen>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Binding the Demo Application to a Phone Number.</title>
		<para>Now we have RestComm deployed and we're ready to bind a phone number to the demo application and finally call the
		phone number to see what happens. In order to interact with RestComm we have provided a set of Restful APIs which are
		very similar to Twilio's Restful APIs. You will learn more about these APIs in a later chapter. We will be using Curl
		to interact with these APIs through out the rest of this guide.</para>
		<note>
			<para>There are wrapper libraries available to interact with RestComm and facilitate interaction for many of the
			popular development platforms.</para>
		</note>
		<para>With the following Curl command we will bind the demo application located @
		http://127.0.0.1:8080/restcomm/demo/hello-world.xml to phone number 1234.</para>
		<screen>
		~]$ curl --data "PhoneNumber=1234&amp;VoiceUrl=http://127.0.0.1:8080/restcomm/demo/hello-world.xml&amp;VoiceMethod=POST"
http://ACae6e420f425248d6a26948c17a9e2acf:77f8c12cc7b8f8423e5c38b035249166@127.0.0.1:8080/restcomm/2012-04-24/Accounts/ACae6e420f425248d6a26948c17a9e2acf/IncomingPhoneNumbers.json
		</screen>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Making the First Call!</title>
		<para>Finally, spin up your favorite softphone and dial sip:1234@127.0.0.1:5080</para>
	</section>
	<para>Keep in mind that before you continue you should configure your ASR, Fax, SMS, and TTS plugins in order to have
	everything function as you would expect it to.</para>
</chapter>
