<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "RestComm_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter>
	<title>Introduction to &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME;</title>
	<para>&SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME;
		is a Communications Platform to rapidly build fax, voice, and text messaging
		applications, using your existing web development skills.
	</para>
	<para>
		It's a complete turnkey Telco 2.0 SaaS solution ready to deploy in
		your cloud based on the
		<ulink url="www.twilio.com">Twilio</ulink>
		simple and effective APIs and 100% Open Source built on the next
		generation Cloud Communications platform &PLATFORM_NAME;.
	</para>
	<section>
		<title>How it Works</title>
		<para>In order to demonstrate how &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME; works we will go over an application that
		instructs &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME; to answer a phone call, say "Hello World" and finally hang up the
		call.</para>
		<note>
			<para>A more thorough explanation of the &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME; Markup Language is available in Chapter 3. &SHORT_PLATFORM_NAME;
		    Markup Language</para>
		</note>
		<para>In this particular example, the first thing that must happen is that TelScale RestComm receives a call.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/restcomm-inbound-1.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>After TelScale RestComm can confirm that the call is destined for an application that it handles. 
		TelScale RestComm calls out to your application for instructions on how to handle the new incoming call.
		Keep in mind that when TelScale RestComm calls out to your application it provides useful information such
		as from what number the call was dialed, to what number the call is destined, caller ID information, etc.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/restcomm-inbound-2.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>Once your application responds with instructions on how to handle the call, TelScale RestComm gets busy executing the
		provided instruction set.</para>
		<programlisting role="XML">
		&lt;Response&gt;
		  &lt;Say&gt;Hello World!&lt;/Say&gt;
		&lt;/Response&gt;
		</programlisting>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/restcomm-inbound-3.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>In this case TelScale RestComm synthesizes the text to speech, says "Hello World!" to the caller and hangs up.</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/restcomm-inbound-4.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	<para>Keep in mind that before you continue you should configure your ASR, Fax, SMS, and TTS plugins in order to have
	everything function as you would expect it to.</para>
</chapter>
