<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../RestComm_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section>
	<title>Document Conventions</title>
	<para>
		This manual uses several conventions to highlight certain words
		and phrases and draw attention to specific pieces of information.
	</para>
	<para>
		In PDF and paper editions, this manual uses typefaces drawn from the
		<ulink url="https://fedorahosted.org/liberation-fonts/">Liberation Fonts</ulink>
		set. The Liberation Fonts set is also used in HTML editions if the set
		is installed on your system. If not, alternative but equivalent
		typefaces are displayed. Note: Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5 and later
		includes the Liberation Fonts set by default.
	</para>
	<section>
		<title>Typographic Conventions</title>
		<para>
			Four typographic conventions are used to call attention to
			specific words and phrases. These conventions, and the circumstances
			they apply to, are as follows.
		</para>
		<para>
			<literal>Mono-spaced Bold</literal>
		</para>
		<para>
			Used to highlight system input, including shell commands, file
			names and paths. Also used to highlight key caps and
			key-combinations. For example:
		</para>
		<blockquote>
			<para>
				To see the contents of the file
				<filename>my_next_bestselling_novel</filename>
				in your current working directory, enter the
				<command>cat my_next_bestselling_novel</command>
				command at the shell prompt and press
				<keycap>Enter</keycap>
				to execute the command.
			</para>
		</blockquote>
		<para>
			The above includes a file name, a shell command and a key cap,
			all presented in Mono-spaced Bold and all distinguishable thanks to
			context.
		</para>
		<para>
			Key-combinations can be distinguished from key caps by the
			hyphen connecting each part of a key-combination. For example:
		</para>
		<blockquote>
			<para>
				Press
				<keycap>Enter</keycap>
				to execute the command.
			</para>
			<para>
				Press
				<keycombo>
					<keycap>Ctrl</keycap>
					<keycap>Alt</keycap>
					<keycap>F1</keycap>
				</keycombo>
				to switch to the first virtual terminal. Press
				<keycombo>
					<keycap>Ctrl</keycap>
					<keycap>Alt</keycap>
					<keycap>F7</keycap>
				</keycombo>
				to return to your X-Windows session.
			</para>
		</blockquote>
		<para>
			The first sentence highlights the particular key cap to press.
			The second highlights two sets of three key caps, each set pressed
			simultaneously.
		</para>
		<para>
			If source code is discussed, class names, methods, functions,
			variable names and returned values mentioned within a paragraph will
			be presented as above, in
			<literal>Mono-spaced Bold</literal>
			. For example:
		</para>
		<blockquote>
			<para>
				File-related classes include
				<classname>filesystem</classname>
				for file systems,
				<classname>file</classname>
				for files, and
				<classname>dir</classname>
				for directories. Each class has its own associated set of
				permissions.
			</para>
		</blockquote>
		<para>
			<application>Proportional Bold</application>
		</para>
		<para>
			This denotes words or phrases encountered on a system, including
			application names; dialogue box text; labelled buttons; check-box and
			radio button labels; menu titles and sub-menu titles. For example:
		</para>
		<blockquote>
			<para>
				Choose
				<guimenu>System &gt; Preferences &gt; Mouse</guimenu>
				from the main menu bar to launch
				<application>Mouse Preferences</application>
				. In the
				<guilabel>Buttons</guilabel>
				tab, click the
				<guilabel>Left-handed mouse</guilabel>
				check box and click
				<guibutton>Close</guibutton>
				to switch the primary mouse button from the left to the right
				(making the mouse suitable for use in the left hand).
			</para>
			<para>
				To insert a special character into a
				<application>gedit</application>
				file, choose
				<guimenu>Applications &gt; Accessories &gt; Character Map</guimenu>
				from the main menu bar. Next, choose
				<guimenu>Search &gt; Find&hellip;</guimenu>
				from the
				<application>Character Map</application>
				menu bar, type the name of the character in the
				<guilabel>Search</guilabel>
				field and click
				<guibutton>Next</guibutton>
				. The character you sought will be highlighted in the
				<guilabel>Character Table</guilabel>
				. Double-click this highlighted character to place it in the
				<guilabel>Text to copy</guilabel>
				field and then click the
				<guibutton>Copy</guibutton>
				button. Now switch back to your document and choose
				<guimenu>Edit &gt; Paste</guimenu>
				from the
				<application>gedit</application>
				menu bar.
			</para>
		</blockquote>
		<para>
			The above text includes application names; system-wide menu
			names and items; application-specific menu names; and buttons and
			text found within a GUI interface, all presented in Proportional Bold
			and all distinguishable by context.
		</para>
		<para>
			Note the
			<guimenu>&gt;</guimenu>
			shorthand used to indicate traversal through a menu and its
			sub-menus. This is to avoid the difficult-to-follow &#39;Select
			<guimenuitem>Mouse</guimenuitem>
			from the
			<guimenu>Preferences</guimenu>
			sub-menu in the
			<guimenu>System</guimenu>
			menu of the main menu bar&#39; approach.
		</para>
		<para>
			<command>
				<replaceable>Mono-spaced Bold Italic</replaceable>
			</command>
			or
			<application>
				<replaceable>Proportional Bold Italic</replaceable>
			</application>
		</para>
		<para>
			Whether Mono-spaced Bold or Proportional Bold, the addition of
			Italics indicates replaceable or variable text. Italics denotes text
			you do not input literally or displayed text that changes depending
			on circumstance. For example:
		</para>
		<blockquote>
			<para>
				To connect to a remote machine using ssh, type
				<command>
					ssh
					<replaceable>username</replaceable>
					@
					<replaceable>domain.name</replaceable>
				</command>
				at a shell prompt. If the remote machine is
				<filename>example.com</filename>
				and your username on that machine is john, type
				<command>ssh john@example.com</command>
				.
			</para>
			<para>
				The
				<command>
					mount -o remount
					<replaceable>file-system</replaceable>
				</command>
				command remounts the named file system. For example, to remount the
				<filename>/home</filename>
				file system, the command is
				<command>mount -o remount /home</command>
				.
			</para>
			<para>
				To see the version of a currently installed package, use the
				<command>
					rpm -q
					<replaceable>package</replaceable>
				</command>
				command. It will return a result as follows:
				<command>
					<replaceable>package-version-release</replaceable>
				</command>
				.
			</para>
		</blockquote>
		<para>
			Note the words in bold italics above &mdash; username,
			domain.name, file-system, package, version and release. Each word is
			a placeholder, either for text you enter when issuing a command or
			for text displayed by the system.
		</para>
		<para>
			Aside from standard usage for presenting the title of a work,
			italics denotes the first use of a new and important term. For
			example:
		</para>
		<blockquote>
			<para>
				When the Apache HTTP Server accepts requests, it dispatches child
				processes or threads to handle them. This group of child processes
				or threads is known as a
				<firstterm>server-pool</firstterm>
				. Under Apache HTTP Server 2.0, the responsibility for creating and
				maintaining these server-pools has been abstracted to a group of
				modules called
				<firstterm>Multi-Processing Modules</firstterm>
				(
				<firstterm>MPMs</firstterm>
				). Unlike other modules, only one module from the MPM group can be
				loaded by the Apache HTTP Server.
			</para>
		</blockquote>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Pull-quote Conventions</title>
		<para>
			Two, commonly multi-line, data types are set off visually from
			the surrounding text.
		</para>
		<para>
			Output sent to a terminal is set in
			<computeroutput>Mono-spaced Roman</computeroutput>
			and presented thus:
		</para>

		<screen>
books        Desktop   documentation  drafts  mss    photos   stuff  svn
books_tests  Desktop1  downloads      images  notes  scripts  svgs
</screen>
		<para>
			Source-code listings are also set in
			<computeroutput>Mono-spaced Roman</computeroutput>
			but are presented and highlighted as follows:
		</para>

		<programlisting language="Java">
package org.jboss.book.jca.ex1;

import javax.naming.InitialContext;

public class ExClient
{
   public static void main(String args[]) 
       throws Exception
   {
      InitialContext iniCtx = new InitialContext();
      Object         ref    = iniCtx.lookup("EchoBean");
      EchoHome       home   = (EchoHome) ref;
      Echo           echo   = home.create();

      System.out.println("Created Echo");

      System.out.println("Echo.echo(&#39;Hello&#39;) = " + echo.echo("Hello"));
   }
   
}
</programlisting>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Notes and Warnings</title>
		<para>
			Finally, we use three visual styles to draw attention to
			information that might otherwise be overlooked.
		</para>
		<note>
			<title>Note</title>
			<para>
				A note is a tip or shortcut or alternative approach to the task
				at hand. Ignoring a note should have no negative consequences, but
				you might miss out on a trick that makes your life easier.
			</para>
		</note>
		<important>
			<title>Important</title>
			<para>
				Important boxes detail things that are easily missed:
				configuration changes that only apply to the current session, or
				services that need restarting before an update will apply. Ignoring
				Important boxes won&#39;t cause data loss but may cause irritation
				and frustration.
			</para>
		</important>
		<warning>
			<title>Warning</title>
			<para>
				A Warning should not be ignored. Ignoring warnings will most
				likely cause data loss.
			</para>
		</warning>
	</section>

</section>


